

Details

LOCATION

P Cluj-Napoca, Romania

+40 754 921 191

✓ vlad.blaj@bitladssoftware.com

NATIONALITY

Romanian

Links

Linkedin

Github

Bitlads Software

Skills

| Java | 6+ years |
|--------------|-----------|
| React | 5+ years |
| Typescript | 1 year |
| Spring Boot | 5 years |
| React Native | 2 years |
| Python | 1 year |
| AWS | 1+ years |
| | |
| Languages | |
| English | 15+ years |
| German | 3 years |
| | |

Courses

Pega - Pega Certified System Architect (CSA)

Scrum Alliance - Scrum Alliance Certified Scrum Master

Vlad Blaj

Senior Full Stack Developer • Freelancer • Contractor • Founder of Bitlads Software

About me

I am a Full Stack Developer with **6+ years of experience** eager to put in practice all the newest technologies, only interested in remote work. I have excellent planning skills, an effective time management system with which I am able to meet required deadlines. Confident in myself but always open to new ideas and suggestions.

Employment History

Senior Full Stack Developer at Aera Technology

ROMANIA AUGUST 2019 — PRESENT

Aera is a Cognitive Operating System that connects you with your business and autonomously orchestrates your operations. It enables this by creating processes with a drag and drop system which transform to executable programs.

- Improved process throughput execution by 40% by creating a Scheduler using Java and Quartz framework capable of executing high amounts of tasks across multiple nodes spread across multiple time zones.
- Built and designed a React/Redux User Interface capable of running different machine learning models.
- Optimized process execution time by an average of 60% by creating a Java Profiler with a React Front-End capable of analyzing and gathering data about different Aera Client Processes.

Skills: Java, React, Spring Boot, Spring, Typescript, Redux, Apache Cassandra, Kafka, Redis, Quartz, AWS, Microservices

Full Stack Developer at .msg Systems

ROMANNIA JULY 2017 - AUGUST 2019

Designed and developed a Web and Mobile Application used by Hilti's sales staff before, during and after customer visits to identify potential agreements and contact Hilti customers to evaluate and redefine existing agreements.

- Increased KPIs target values by 30% by creating a Java KPI aggregator tool for different sales and prices. Used different design patterns (e.g. Decorator, Strategy, Template, Builder, Observer).
- Increased team productivity and overall new employees ramp up time by being heavily involved in their training process and by taking the role of a scrum master.

Skills: Java, React, Spring Boot, Redux, Hana Cloud Platform, Apache Olingo, SAP HANA, Junit, Mockito, JIRA, Bamboo, Flyway, Swagger, Hibernate, Microservices

Java Software Developer at .msg Systems

ROMANIA - JULY 2014 — JULY 2017

The client needed a tool to view filter and process candidates for different hiring positions. Previously Excel sheets were used to aggregate and process candidates. I developed and optimized a React Application which can process large number of candidates.

 Created a React/Redux hiring platform for new employees which increased the hiring speed process and the number of candidates which could be processed during a hiring period by 50%.

Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, React, Liferay, Selenium, MySql

Personal Projects

Samson iOS YouTube App, Cluj-Napoca

ROMANIA JANUARY 2021 - JULY 2021

I Developed a React Native App in which the user is able to create **custom YouTube Playlists**. All playback functionalities are available plus the ability to view videos on YouTube using a **picture-in-picture capabilities**.

Added previously inexistent functionalities like playing cropped videos.

Skills: React Native, Expo, Animated View, React Native Router Flux, Redux, Native Base

Binance Trading Bot

ROMANIA SEPTEMBER 2020 — JUNE 2021

I created a Trading Bot capable of executing orders based on a given set of trading strategies. The bot would be connected to Binance API through websockets. The program is also able to backtest different strategies and estimate returns.

- Created a 5% per week return automated trade strategy.
- Added a React User Interface capable of displaying real time trading charts.

Skills: Python, React, Java (Pandas, NumPy, TimeSeries and Matplot lib)

Education

Masters Degree, Babes Bolyai University

ROMANIA, CLUJ-NAPOCA, OCTOBER 2015 — JULY 2017

Thesis: Improved "Detecting Energy Leak Bugs in Android Applications"

• Optimized and increased the code static analysis speed by more than 40%.

Skills: Java, ANTLR, MySql

Bachelor Degree, Babes Bolyai University

ROMANIA CLUJ-NAPOCA, OCTOBER 2021 — JULY 2015

Thesis: Detecting Energy Leak Bugs in Android Applications.

I developed a program using Java which will detect and signal the presence of no-sleep-energy-bugs (battery drain bugs). It is a static analysis of the source code of an android project.

• Reduced battery usage for different Android Applications by more than 15%.

Skills: Java, ANTLR 4.5, IntelliJ Plugin Development API